<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jatinder Pal on Jatinder Pal</title>
    <link>https://jatinderpal.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jatinder Pal on Jatinder Pal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>LU-SGS</title>
      <link>https://jatinderpal.com/post/lusgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 18:37:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jatinderpal.com/post/lusgs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lower Upper Symmertic Gauss Sidel method is matrix free implicit time-integration scheme.
If we spatilly discretize any governing eqution; using any one of the well known methods: Finite difference method, Finite Volume method, Finite element method, etc; we as left with system of odinary differential equations.
$$V\frac{dU_i}{dt} = R_i^{n+1}$$
Where, &amp;ldquo;$i$&amp;rdquo; represents the cell center or cell node point based on the spatial discrtization method.
U and R are the state  and residual vector stored at spatial point &amp;ldquo;$i$&amp;rdquo;. $V$ represents the volume of the cell.
To integrate this system of ODE we can use Euler time integration scheme:
$$V\frac{\Delta U^n_i}{\Delta t} = R_i^{n+1}$$
Where $\Delta t$ is the time increment and $\Delta U^n_i$ represents the difference between state vector at time level $n+1$ and $n$: $U^{n+1}_i - U^n_i$. Since $R^{n+1}_i$ is unkonw, we linearize the above equation to approximate unknown quantity, $R^{n+1}_i$ in terms of known quantities.
$$V\frac{\Delta U^n_i}{\Delta t} = R_i^{n} + \left(\frac{\partial R}{\partial U}\right)^n\Delta U_i^n$$
Rearranging the above equation to combine all the $\Delta U^n_i$ terms:
$$\left(\frac{V}{\Delta t} + \left(\frac{\partial R}{\partial U}\right)^n\right)\Delta U_i^n  = R_i^{n}$$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Ramp-Type Micro Vortex Generators Using Swirl Center Tracking</title>
      <link>https://jatinderpal.com/publication/2018aiaajour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jatinderpal.com/publication/2018aiaajour/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A convergence study of solutions using two two-equation RANS turbulence models on a finite volume solver for structured grids</title>
      <link>https://jatinderpal.com/publication/2018aiaaconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jatinderpal.com/publication/2018aiaaconf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FEST3D</title>
      <link>https://jatinderpal.com/project/fest3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jatinderpal.com/project/fest3d/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A convergence study of solutions using two two-equation RANS turbulence models on a finite volume solver for structured grids</title>
      <link>https://jatinderpal.com/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jatinderpal.com/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Some Wedge-shaped Vortex Generators Using Swirl Center Tracking</title>
      <link>https://jatinderpal.com/publication/2016aiaaconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jatinderpal.com/publication/2016aiaaconf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vortex Generator</title>
      <link>https://jatinderpal.com/project/vortexgenerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jatinderpal.com/project/vortexgenerator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vortex generators have shown promise in reducing, if not completely removing, flow separation due to shock-boundary layer interaction. These devices introduce a set of co-rotating or counter-rotating vortex pairs into the flow, which are considered to make the streamwise velocity profile fuller (near the wall), effectively increasing the ability of the flow to withstand higher adverse pressure gradient without undergoing separation. A sub-class of vortex generators is the ramp-type or wedge-shaped vortex generator (other being vane type) that produces a counter-rotating vortex pair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the flow-field downstream of a ramp-type vortex-generator, as the counter-rotating vortex pair is advected by the mean flow, it is lifted off due to the mutual up wash. To an extent, the effectiveness of these vortices depends on how fast these vortices lift off, as vortices that lift off at a slower rate remain closer to the wall over longer distance downstream of the device trailing edge, and potentially have a greater energizing effect on the near wall flow. In this work, the evolution of the primary vortex pair downstream of vortex generators placed in a supersonic stream is compared using a swirl center tracking technique, for standard, slotted, and split-ramp type vortex generators.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
